Welcome back
and this is going to be a filler episode
So I'm mostly going to talk 20 minutes on how to craft an electrolyzer
how to pick the recipes for crafting it
and that's going to be it
Next episode I'm going to actually do some infrastructure, hopefully
So if you want a bunch of random tips for MV and LV
go ahead and watch the rest
If you just want to see me building infrastructure
just skip this episode, go to the next one
because this episode is just going to be a filler about crafting an electrolyzer
Welcome back
and today we are going to start the MV tier
Now, last episode I didn't even finish the circuits
because I wasn't sure which recipe to go with the diodes
and I think this tier we are going to see today
is mostly going to be about figuring out how we want to do things and which recipes to use
And that issue will start right away from the next quest
getting a circuit board
The quest book here makes you think that you should go with this recipe
which I think is totally wrong
because if you make a good circuit board like that
you're going to need four gold ingots to make a circuit board
but if you go with this way you can only use one ingot
So this recipe is four times cheaper on gold
and I think it's totally worth to use that recipe
And of course, once again we have to choose if we want to do iron III chloride or sodium persulfate
I think that can be a good exercise to figure out NEI and look around at which way you rather do
And I've decided to go with iron III chloride
which is probably a little bit easier
because sodium persulfate is easier if you already have sulfuric acid
I would have got this from oil processing, maybe
but, I think I just go with iron III chloride (?)
Also, you need less iron III chloride
If you use sodium persulfate you need twice as much
but once again you can have this one in bigger bulks
So anyways, to get this one we are going to need some hydrochloric acid
That's the main issue, but the issue really is hydrogen
Now the laziest way of getting hydrogen is to just electrolyze some water
but that is also the slowest possible way of doing it
because it takes 50 seconds at full power for one cell
The better way, which is a little bit more annoying however to do, is to simply centrifuge some limonite
So I already got here some limonite
We wash it
This one goes into a centrifuge with a cell
And of course that is the centrifuge I'm using too
So it should be quite fast
We should get another hatch
OKay, that should make it work
Come on
OKay, good
Getting hydrogen from a steam centrifuge
Half a minute to get six cells of hydrogen
That basically fills up the output hatch
Once it's done, we collect the hydrogen
And I like to use the large cells
Choose whatever cells you have available really
I really like the large cells
but you can totally work with those
You have to use those in the recipes anyways later
But anyways, you only need a little bit of hydrogen because then it loops
Let's get there and you will see
The second ingredient is going to be some chlorine
Now chlorine, you most likely want to get it out of salt
And if you use rock salt, it should be better
Let me check so, chlorine
Yeah, it takes some time to see everything
I rush on my things. (?)
Rock salt takes 4 seconds, while normal salt takes 16 seconds
It's like 5 times faster normal rock salt
Sodium may be a little bit more useful than potassium
but at the beginning...
(it's/that's going to?) go with this one
I mean, I'm not using the electrolyzer for anything else
So I could just leave it work
But let's (wait?) this way
OKay, got some rock salt
I'm going to process more later
OKay, that should quickly get us the chlorine
This is something that most likely you want to have a dedicated machine for
Right now I'm doing it because...
Right now my setup is super small, tight and ugly
Later on, when I have things setup a little better, I'm going to passivate
Usually I will passivate from the first usage, so I never do it manually
But doing things manually is also nice sometimes
And I just figured out I have never made a chemical reactor so far
OKay, I got a chemical reactor
Circuit one, hydrogen and chlorine
And that should get us the hydrochloric acid
Good
And now that we have that, we can finish it off by adding iron dust
And there we go
We also got the hydrogen back, which we can use to make more later
But we don't really need much of this
Two buckets is already enough for 20 circuits
But I'm going to make just two circuits right now
We will talk about this soon
Meanwhile I already got the gold foil
and this thing...
which goes back in there
with a little bit of that
And we get the circuit boards
The other thing we needed was the diodes
The other thing we need is diodes
Those are made from gallium arsenide
Why did this one not (?)
OKay, we got this one
Now, as I said in the last episode
ideally I will try to get polyethylene and wafers to get a lot of diodes
But this run, I decided to do things differently
so I'm going to rush through the circuits
and then I will work slightly differently
So, I got those
If I went with the silicon boules, I would have to forge hammer into the tiny version
but instead I'm going to macerate it to get the dust
Actually, you know what, I'm macerating both of those
This one is busy, let's use this one
OK, while it macerates the other thing we need is glass
now there are two different glasses
one is the Tinker's Construct
the other one is the GregTech one
you can put a bucket...
to get this one, you put glass dust inside this smeltery
you put a bucket in there
and you pour it out
maybe that's a way I could do
the GregTech one, ideally you want to use glass or sand
but that requires MV, we don't have MV
so I think I have some (?)
yeah you can do it (with quartzite at LV?)
but it's one minute to get one glass
at this point I think I would rather use this smeltery
so let's get a little bit of quartz sand
gosh I have to macerate more stuff
to get sand it's easy
soon there would be a better way of getting glass too
you need a MV arc furnace which we are going to get later
but okay to get sand also...
oh there are sand crops
I'm going to do crops in the future
right now... I like to do crops after I get world accelerators
the new crops should be really nice to work with
theoretically, you can do those like in stone age
but I feel like I have better things I can do in stone age
I'd rather do those while I'm waiting for something else and when I already have the world accelerators
anyways, I was looking for...
okay I wanted to show, to get sand, I think it's easier to just forge hammer some gravel
and you get gravel from forge hammering cobblestone
I mean you can go dig the sand or the gravel
but most likely you have so much cobblestone from using the hammer that...
just forge hammer it, it's super easy super fast
and then I was going to do glass the ugly way
which means sand into quartz sand and then into glass dust
there we go
and I made way too much
we only need how much per diode?
one bucket I think, yeah one bucket two diodes
I'm going to do just two of those
because I'm only going to make two circuits
and then I will wait basically half of the video before making more
ideally I'm going to use those two circuits for an electrolyzer
but ideally you should really get a circuit assembler
anyways once it's molten we move it down, put the buckets there
And we should be able to, yes, get the glass like that inside the bucket
does it work? well it should, okay
there we got one of those buckets
the stuff goes into the assembler
one two
this one must be, what is it
okay oh I think if I had annealed copper
yeah annealed copper probably works better
but I think I have to use poly...
there are some combinations which maybe don't work
let's see, annealed...
yeah you need polyethylene to use annealed copper
so I'm not even bothering
I didn't get an arc furnace yet
you can get an arc furnace at this point
like I can get a LV arc furnace for annealed copper and cast iron
they renamed wrought iron into cast iron by the way
what the heck
okay they changed many things since the last time I played
so that is how you get it now, cool
okay now I'm wondering if it is worth it
that thing has some fuel value
but okay anyways I'm skipping to a MV arc furnace which can do better stuff
And that remind me of something I didn't really explain properly in the previous episode
Earlier on, to get cast iron, we have to compress nuggets
which we would have to make by smelting a nugget again
and maybe some people would go with this recipe and mold ingots into nuggets
now instead of doing that, you can smelt a pure iron ore into nuggets
The thing is that, every pure metal
like crushed iron, crushed copper, crushed silver, crushed gold
will give you 10 nuggets instead of an ingot
to use something like pyrite, it will give you an iron ingot
so you can get either ingots or nuggets depending on what it is
the rule is if it is a pure metal, it will give you 10 nuggets
if it is an oxide, it will give you one ingot
Sometimes you want the nuggets, sometimes the ingot
If you want to force the ingot, you can just forge hammer it
and then the crushed dust will always melt into an ingot
but to make cast iron, it's quite nice to get the nuggets this way
meanwhile there is stuff like copper which I think is super annoying if it gives you nuggets
but as I said in the previous episode
you probably want to process copper differently to get the gold dust
so try to figure out how you want to process the different ores
anyways I don't even know how I got into that
but we can now have the diodes
which we can use to make the MV circuits finally
come on
oh, did I forget something?
OH! This quest book wanted these
And now that we have 16 diodes
we can finally make a few circuits after my plan got changed so many times
Now, the first circuit we have to make it with the crafting recipe in the crafting table
which takes three of those circuits
and then I guess we're going to get a circuit assembler (break the cue) so that we can use only two circuits to make one MV
and there we go
okay we got our circuit assembler
and now we can start assembling circuits
now once again always check the recipes because this circuit here too will now be way cheaper
instead of...
maybe not even that much
we save basically a little bit of steel and the rubber, we save the rubber
and also once again, I didn't show it up
but you can make vacuum tubes way cheaper inside an assembler rather than in those recipes
like mostly MV is the tier where you really want to check all of your recipes
I heavily suggest removing the favorite from all of those recipes that are not too good
once again at the beginning of a few episodes ago
I said that just because you can make things with a better recipe you don't have to
MV is where you really have to start considering when it's worth to do a recipe the better way
and when it's worth making it manually
depending on time, cost and other things
by the way I'm using soldering alloy here
but most likely at this tier you want to use a normal lead
because soldering alloy takes tin which is used quite a lot so you have to go dig it
while you probably have some leftover lead by...
When you collect cryolite, it's in the same vein...
So most likely once you start collect more cryolite, you will have a lot of leftover lead
May as well use the lead
Like, you need more of it
but lead is useless, may as well use it
And then we use the new circuit assembler to re-craft those circuits with the cheaper recipe
The only thing left to do is to get the copper cables for the electrolyzer
Those cannot be made in a crafting table, I've been using it so far, so we need an assembler
And at this point I heavily suggest having a dedicated assembler plus chemical reactor setup
to get the rubber, to get the cable coating done constantly
And there we have it
Just leave cables in there and it should work
I think I forgot to connect power
Yes, ok, power connected, now it works
And we should get our copper cables
Which we use to make the first machine you should aim at in MV, the electrolyzer
This one will allow you to get aluminum in many ways you could not access earlier
Before this one getting aluminum is hard
but this one will make sourcing raw aluminum and alumina super easy
I got quite a bunch of aluminum, so I may as well do a MV steam turbine
but you can use a transformer from LV to step it up to MV
Also in MV we will soon get the extruder capable of doing efficient rods
In other GregTech modpacks you get two rods out of one ingot
GTNH you need an extruder to do that, which we will get soon in MV
but here we...
I'm using the lathe only on a few things like aluminum
I wanted to save a little bit of aluminum
Still, there we have our steam turbine
Which can power the electrolyzer
Did I forget to check-mark the quests?
And I didn't get the quests because I didn't get that machine hull in my bag
OK, so I think at this point this episode is not really fit to be an episode
I'm going to do an actual MV episode where I will be talking more about the actual progress
how to lay down cables, etc, etc
I feel like...
What I added so far is not worth of a true episode
so I'm going to call it a half episode or something
So I'm going to stop there
and do the actual MV episode (merge to the upper and lower cue) where I think I'm going to try to centralize power and do some better automation
as another episode
Think of today I fit into that episode right here
Many tips I forgot to put in the previous episode
It's going to be a half episode
There is another thing I want to prepare for the next episode
Which is a trash can, that will require an ender pearl
Which at this point of the game the easiest way of getting it is probably by buying enderman spawn eggs
Now, spawn enderman...
No, NO!
I still have to figure out how I have to click to favorite something
OK
So you get the spawn enderman thing
In the future we will be able to make a on demand power spawners
but right now we have to do it like that
Make sure the top of this smeltery does not view the sun
otherwise the enderman will teleport out
And then you can just drop it in there
And that should get you a lot of liquid ender
We're going to need a little bit of time and it will get up
And then to pour out all of those
Which is actually nothing
You can use a pipe
So you can connect the pipe like this
And then like that
Put this one there
And it should just...
work
Fills up the pipe and fills up this one
This way you don't have to keep clicking
And also don't forget to actually collect the ender pearls
You can get a regenerating enderman or something better
You can make a lot of ender pearls
I didn't get any (?)
But you can get way more
Lead and cryolite are in the same vein
欢迎回来
这期是一集过渡集
所以我是打算花 20 分钟讲怎么制作电解机
怎么选制作配方
就这些
我应该能在下一集真正做一些基建 但愿吧
所以如果你想看一堆 MV 和 LV 的各种小技巧
就继续看下去
如果你只想看我大搞基建
就跳过这集 直接看下一集
因为这集就是个关于制作电解机的过渡集
欢迎回来
今天我们要开始 MV 电压
上一集我连电路板都没做完
因为我不确定二极管用哪个配方
我觉得今天我们在的这个电压
主要是搞清楚我们想怎么做以及用哪些配方
这个问题马上就会从下一个任务开始
获取电路基板
这里的任务书让你觉得应该用这个配方
我觉得这完全错了
因为如果你这样做电路基板
做一块电路基板需要 4 个金锭
但如果用这个配方 只需要 1 个锭
所以这个配方节省四倍的金子
我觉得完全值得用这个配方
当然 我们又得选是用三氯化铁还是过硫酸钠
我觉得这可以作为一个好练习 去看看 NEI 然后搞清楚你更想用哪种方式
我决定用三氯化铁
这可能稍微简单一点
因为过硫酸钠在你已经有硫酸的时候更简单
我可能会从石化中得到这个
但 我想我就用三氯化铁吧（？）
而且三氯化铁需要的更少
如果用过硫酸钠需要两倍
再说一遍 你可以大批量地做这个
所以要得到这个我们需要一些盐酸
那是主要问题 但真正的问题是氢
获取氢最懒人的办法就是电解水
但这也是最慢的方式
因为满功率下一个单元要 50 秒
更好的方法 稍微麻烦一点 就是直接离心一些褐铁矿
所以我已经弄了一些褐铁矿
我们洗一下
这个放进离心机 配一个单元
当然这也是我在用的离心机
所以应该挺快的
我们应该再弄一个仓
好了 这样应该能用了
干活！
好了 不错
从蒸汽离心机获取氢
半分钟得到 6 个单元的氢
基本上填满了输出仓
完成后我们收集氢
我喜欢用大单元
用你手头有的单元就行
我真的很喜欢大单元
但用那些小单元也完全可以
反正后面配方里也得用那些
但不管怎样 你只需要一点氢 因为之后它会循环
做到那一步你就知道了
第二种原料是一些氯
氯 你很可能想从盐里提取
如果用岩盐应该更好
让我查一下 氯
对 看清所有东西需要点时间
我太赶了（？）
岩盐要 4 秒 而普通盐要 16 秒
岩盐差不多快五倍
钠可能比钾有用一点
但在前期……
我们就选这个吧
我是说 我又没拿电解机干别的
所以我可以就让它在那跑
但是 我们就这样吧
好 弄到一些岩盐
我稍后会处理更多
好 这应该能很快给我们弄到氯
你很可能想要一台专门的机器来跑这个配方
现在我这样做是因为……
现在我的机器设置超级小、挤、丑
之后等机器设置得好一点 我会做被动产线
通常我从第一次用就会做被动产线 所以我从不用手动做
但手动做有时候也不错
而且我刚发现我到现在都没做过化学反应釜
好 我做了一个化学反应釜
1 号编程电路 氢和氯
这应该能做盐酸
好
现在我们有了这个 可以加铁粉来完成
好了
我们还回收了氢 之后可以用来做更多
但我们其实不需要太多
两桶已经够做 20 个电路板
但我现在只要做两个电路板
我们很快会讲到这个
与此同时我已经弄到了金箔
而这个东西……
把它放回里面
加一点点那个
然后我们得到了电路基板
我们需要的另一件东西是二极管
它们是用砷化镓做的
这个怎么没有（完成？）
好 我们弄到了这个
正如我上集所说
理想情况下我会试着弄聚乙烯和晶圆来做大量二极管
但这一周目我决定换个做法
所以我会快速搞定电路板
然后我会稍微换个方式
所以 我弄到了那些
如果用单晶硅 我得用锻造锤敲成小型的
但我打算把它研磨成粉
实际上 你知道吗 我两个都研磨
这台在忙 用这台吧
好 研磨的同时 我们需要的另一件东西是玻璃
现在有两种不同的玻璃
一种是匠魂的
另一种是格雷科技的
你可以放一个桶……
要得到这个 你把玻璃粉放进这个冶炼炉里
你放一个桶进去
然后倒出来
也许我可以用那种方式
格雷科技的那种 理想情况下你想用玻璃或沙子
但那需要 MV 我们还没有到 MV
所以我想我有一些（？）
对 你可以在 LV 用石英岩做玻璃
但做一块玻璃要一分钟
这个阶段我觉得我宁愿用这个冶炼炉
所以我们来弄点石英砂
天哪 我还得研磨更多东西
弄沙子很简单
很快会有更好的方法来弄玻璃
你需要一台 MV 电弧炉 我们之后会弄
但好吧 弄沙子也……
哦 有沙子作物
我以后会种作物
现在……我喜欢在拿到世界加速器之后种作物
新的作物应该很好用
理论上 你在石器时代就能种
但我觉得在石器时代我有更好的事情可以做
我宁愿在等别的东西的时候做 而且那时候我已经有世界加速器了
不管怎样 我在找……
好 我想演示一下 要获得沙子 我觉得直接用锻造锤敲沙砾更简单
而沙砾是用锻造锤敲圆石得到的
我是说 你可以去挖沙子或沙砾
但你用锤子大概率已经有了超多圆石……
直接用锻造锤敲 超简单 超快
然后我打算用丑陋的方式做玻璃
也就是沙子变成石英砂再变成玻璃粉
好了
我做了太多了
每个二极管需要多少？
一桶吧 嗯 一桶两个二极管
我只做两个
因为我只做两个电路板
然后我基本会等差不多半个视频再做更多
理想情况下我会用那两个电路板做电解机
但理想情况下你真的应该弄一台电路组装机
不管怎样 一旦熔化我们把它移下来 把桶放那儿
我们应该能 对 就这样把玻璃装进桶里
行吗？应该行吧 好
我们得到了一个有熔融玻璃的桶
东西放进组装机
一桶 两桶
这个必须是 是什么呢
好 哦 我觉得如果我有退火铜
嗯 退火铜可能更好用
但我觉得我得用聚……
有些组合可能不行
看看 退火……
对 你需要聚乙烯才能用退火铜
所以我都不费心了
我还没弄到电弧炉
这个时候你可以弄一台电弧炉
比如我可以弄一台 LV 电弧炉来做退火铜和铸铁
顺便说一下 他们把 wrought iron 改名成 cast iron 了
搞什么
好吧 自从我上次玩之后他们改了很多东西
所以现在就是这样弄的 酷
好 现在我在想值不值得
那个东西有一些燃值
但好吧 不管怎样 我要跳到能做更好的东西的 MV 电弧炉
这让我想起上集有些东西我没解释清楚
之前 要得到铸铁 我们得压缩粒
而这些粒我们得再熔炼一次
也许有些人会用这个配方 把锭压模成粒
现在不用那样做了 你可以把纯铁矿石熔炼成粒
关键是 各种纯金属矿
比如粉碎铁、粉碎铜、粉碎银、粉碎金
会给你 10 个粒而不是一个锭
用像黄铁矿这样的东西 会给你一个铁锭
所以你可以获得锭或粒 取决于烧的是什么
规则是 如果是纯金属 会给你 10 个粒
如果是氧化物 会给你一个锭
有时候你要粒 有时候要锭
如果你想确定地得到锭 可以直接用锻造锤敲
然后粉碎的粉总会烧成一个锭
但要制作铸铁 用这种方式得到粒挺好的
同时有些东西比如铜 我觉得如果给粒就很烦
但正如我上集所说
你可能想用不同的方式处理铜来得到金粉
所以试着搞清楚你想怎么处理不同的矿石
不管怎样 我都不知道怎么聊到这了
但我们现在可以有二极管了
终于可以用来做 MV 电路板了
拜托
哦 我忘了什么吗？
哦！任务书要的是这些
现在我们有 16 个二极管了
我的计划改了这么多次后终于可以做几个电路板了
第一个电路板我们必须用工作台里的合成配方来做
需要三个那种电路板
然后我猜我们会弄一台电路组装机（断句）这样就能只用两个电路板做一个 MV 的
好了
好 我们弄到了电路组装机
现在可以开始组装电路板了
再说一次 总是检查配方 因为这里的这个电路板也会便宜很多
而不是……
可能也没那么多
我们基本上省了一点钢和橡胶
而且 再一次地 我没展示出来
但你可以在组装机里做真空管 比那些配方便宜多了
比如 MV 基本上是你真的要检查所有配方的电压
我强烈建议把那些不太好的配方的收藏去掉
再说一次 几集之前
我说过 仅仅因为你能用更好的配方做东西 不代表你必须用
MV 是你真的要开始考虑什么时候值得用更好的方式做配方的电压
以及什么时候值得手动做
取决于时间 成本和其他因素
顺便说一下 我这里用的是焊锡
但在这个电压你很可能想用普通的铅
因为焊锡需要锡 而锡用得很多 所以你得去挖
而你可能已经有一些剩的铅……
当你采集冰晶石时 它在同一个矿脉……
所以很可能一旦你开始采集更多冰晶石 你会有很多剩的铅
不如就用铅
尽管（相比焊锡）你需要更多的铅
但铅没什么用 不如就用掉
然后我们用新的电路组装机用更便宜的配方重做那些电路板
唯一剩下要做的是弄电解机用的铜线缆
那些不能在工作台里做 我一直用的是工作台 所以我们需要一台组装机
这时候我强烈建议有一台专门的组装机加化学反应釜的设置
用来不断地做橡胶 做绝缘线缆
做好了
把线缆留在里面就行
我好像忘了接电
对 好 接上电了 现在能用了
我们应该能做出铜线缆
用来做你在 MV 应该优先搞的第一台机器 电解机
这台机器能让你用很多之前无法做到的方式得到铝
在这之前弄到铝很难
但这台会让获取铝和氧化铝变得超级简单
我弄了挺多铝 所以不如做一台 MV 蒸汽轮机
但你可以用变压器从 LV 升压到 MV
而且在 MV 我们很快就能弄到压模机 能高效地做杆
在其他格雷科技整合包里 一个锭能出两个杆
GTNH 里你需要一台压模机才能做到 我们很快会在 MV 弄到
但这里我们……
我只在少数东西上用车床 比如铝
我想省一点铝
不过 我们有了蒸汽轮机
它能给电解机供能
我是不是忘了给任务打勾？
我没完成任务 因为我没把那个机器外壳放进背包
好 所以这时候我觉得这集不太够格做一集
我会做一集真正的 MV 集会更多讲实际进展
怎么布线 等等
我觉得……
我目前加的东西不够格做一集正式的
所以我打算叫它半集之类的
所以我就到这了
然后做真正的 MV 集（向上向下合并）我觉得我会试着集中供能 做些更好的自动化
作为另一集
我觉得今天的内容我塞进这集里了
很多我忘了放进上集的小技巧
会是半集
还有一件我想为下集准备的东西
就是一个垃圾桶 需要一颗末影珍珠
在游戏的这个阶段 最简单的获取方式可能就是买末影人刷怪蛋
好 生成末影人……
不 不对！
我还得搞清楚要怎么点击才能收藏东西
好
所以你拿到了生成末影人的东西
以后我们能做电动刷怪笼
但现在只能这样做
确保这个冶炼炉的顶部晒不到太阳
否则末影人会传送出去
然后你直接把它扔进去
这应该能给你弄到很多熔融末影
过一会它就会积攒起来
然后把那些全倒出来
其实也没多少
你可以用管道
所以你可以像这样连接管道
然后像那样
把这个放那儿
它应该就……
能用
填满管道 然后填满这个
这样你就不用一直点击
还有别忘了收集做好的末影珍珠
你可以弄一个会再生的末影人或者更好的东西
你可以得到很多末影珍珠
我一个都没弄到（？）
但你能弄到多得多
铅和冰晶石在同一个矿脉里（操作失误，这句被分到另外一轨了，剪辑的时候改正）